地心空洞某处
在人类文明的进程中
For most of human civilization,
我们普遍认为 人类是地球上最具优势的物种
we believed that we were Earth's most dominant species.
我们认为只有在地球表面 生命才能存活
We believed that life… could only exist on the surface of the planet.
但过了某个时候 你不禁会思考
Well, after a certain point, you have to wonder
艾琳·安德鲁斯博士
帝王组织 金刚研究部主任
人类还对什么有误解
what else were we wrong about?
（涡旋 地心空洞核心）
我们对于地心空洞的测绘不到5%
We have mapped less than five percent of Hollow Earth.
但地心和地表的生态系统紧密关联超乎想象
But our ecosystems are linked in ways we never could have imagined.
这两个世界不是独立的
We are not two separate worlds.
而是个整体
We're one.
金刚还在适应新环境
Kong is settling in to Hollow Earth.
（纽约时报 金刚迁居地心空洞）
就是说 大块头挺喜欢它新家的
So, the big guy likes his new home.
应该喜欢
We think so.
它的种群热衷于群居
His species was a very social one.
独自生活和它的天性不符
It's not natural for Kong to be so alone.
它没有同类
He's the last of his kind.
每一天都在寻找家人 尽管只是徒劳
Every day he searches for a family that he'll never find.
那哥斯拉呢
What about Godzilla?
哥斯拉在地表 金刚在地下
Godzilla's on the surface, Kong is below.
只要它们不闯入彼此的领地
As long as they don't venture into each other's territories,
就没什么好担心的
we've got nothing to worry about.
人类很幸运
Humanity is lucky…
我们打不了的仗 总有哥斯拉帮忙
Godzilla's fighting the battles we can't.
意大利 罗马
根据日本东宝株式会社的形象「哥斯拉」改编
哥斯拉大战金刚2：帝国崛起
一些批评人士指责
With some critics calling out Monarch
帝王组织将数十亿美元税款
for the billions in taxpayer dollars…
帝王组织1号前哨站 金刚观测点 地心空洞
用于研究地心空洞和机密技术
going to Hollow Earth and classified technologies
比如神秘的动力室项目
like the mysterious Project Powerhouse.
今天我们邀请到了
Well, here to discuss,
帝王组织的艾琳·安德鲁斯博士
Monarch's own, Doctor Ilene Andrews.
先来聊聊哥斯拉吧
Let's start with Godzilla. He stopped the attack in Rome,
为罗马而战后 它一直待在城里
He stopped the attack in Rome, but he's still in the city.
（哥斯拉占据罗马斗兽场 游客心生敬畏纷纷撤离）
这样安全吗
Should we be worried?
首先 我们要知道一点
It's clear to us now
哥斯拉在保护我们
that Godzilla is a Titan who protects us
免遭其它泰坦巨兽的伤害
from other malicious Titan threats.
金刚要去睡了
Kong's heading in for the night.
它今天又不顺心
Looks like it was another rough one.
它还没走过那么远
That's the farthest he's gone yet.
或许它在找对象
Maybe he was looking for a date.
祝它好运
Good luck with that.
希望它能跟别的物种谈个恋爱
I hope he's up for some interspecies romance.
第五区发现沉洞
Sinkhole detected in Sector Five.
（第五区检测到地震活动）
那是金刚的狩猎场
That's Kong's hunting ground.
（发现未知区域）
一直在闪
Whoa. It keeps doing that.
又是电波异常吗
More electrical anomalies?
应该不是 我还没遇到过这种状况
Nah, I don't think so, man. I haven't seen anything like this before.
我去找汉普顿主任
Well, we should tell Director Hampton.
那我去上报 这地方本身就不正常
I'll type it up. This whole place is an anomaly.
太奇怪了
It's so weird.
地心空洞入口 帝王组织 巴巴多斯
告诉意大利军方
Tell the Italian military
要不是有哥斯拉 罗马早就没了
Rome would be flattened if it weren't for Godzilla.
他们爱怎么威胁就怎么威胁
They can threaten him all they want.
让他们另找替罪羊吧
Just tell them to find another scapegoat.
汉普顿主任 什么事
Director Hampton, what's up?
这个 1号前哨站麻烦不断
Well, Outpost One is still a nightmare,
他们发来了这个 你来看看吧
and they sent this over. I thought you might want to take a look.
这是传感器阵列的数据吗
Is this from the sensor array?
对 上面有了一些很奇怪的峰值
Yeah, we've been getting some pretty weird spikes.
也可能是普通的干扰
I mean, it could just be regular interference.
但一直持续
Yeah, but it keeps happening.
应该组个调查队 以防万一
We should prep a survey team just in case.
好的
Okay.
哥斯拉呢
And what about Godzilla?
它还在睡觉
Oh, he's still sleeping.
像个愤怒的巨婴
Like a big angry baby.
希望它能一直这样安静
Let's hope it stays that way.
帝王组织基地学院 巴巴多斯
大家专心答题 明白吧
Everyone, eyes on your own paper, all right?
把你认为正确的选项圈出来
Let's make sure we circle the answers
一定要清晰
really, really clearly.
务必预留出足够的时间
[muffled speaking]
吉雅
Jia!
你的女儿很聪明 但不够专心
Your daughter is intelligent, but she's not engaged.
成绩一直在下滑 也不和别的小朋友玩
Her grades are slipping, she's not interacting with any of her friends.
这些问题不会凭空消失 安德鲁斯博士
And these problems aren't going away, Doctor Andrews.
只会更糟糕
They've been getting worse.
好吧 真是抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry.
她还在适应我们的世界
She's just still adjusting to our world.
我能理解
I understand that,
但学校里面还有很多
but we have a number of students
远离了自己文化的学生
who are culturally displaced and…
没错 但她不是 她就是自己文化的代表
Sure, but her culture's not displaced, she is her culture.
她是伊维族的最后一位幸存者
She's the last living member of the Iwi tribe.
我们只是想帮她
We're just trying to reach her.
我知道
I know.
我何尝不是
你怎么了
没什么
就是担心金刚
你为什么画了这个
可以走了吗
看着我
我不属于这里
我不属于任何地方
你应该在我身边
我也应该在你身边
走吧
Come on.
几百年来 伊维族人一直守护着骷髅岛
For centuries, the Iwi tribe were the guardians of Skull Island,
这里也是金刚的老家
the ancestral home of the great Kong.
但风暴规律变化摧毁了这座岛
But when shifting storm patterns destroyed the island,
伊维族惨遭灭族 只有一个人逃过了这场劫难
the Iwi were annihilated… with only a single member of the tribe having survived.
一个小女孩
A young girl…
被人们在肆虐的暴风雨中救了出来
found and rescued amid the punishing storm.
她的族人们则被大水吞没
Her fellow villagers were lost to the tides.
隐入历史洪流
Gone to history,
就像金刚的同类那般
just like the great Kongs themselves.
不会吧
Holy shit.
伊维族的一大特点是他们没有口头语言
The Iwi were unique… in the sense that they had no spoken language.
（地表声波 地震纵波 地震横波）
（无信号）
（接近传感器警报 监测到活动）
我担心自己出了问题
你没有任何问题
你很完美
我感觉自己快疯了
我们一定会有办法的
We're gonna figure this out.
佛罗里达州 迈阿密
下次巨兽来袭时你会在哪
Where will you be when the next Titan attacks?
你要如何保护自己珍视的…
How will you protect the things and people…
人和物
that matter most to you?
本期播客由巨人保险赞助
Today's podcast is brought to you by Gargantua insurance,
唯一为你们的家和个人财物
The only insurance company that provides Titan protection
提供巨大保护的保险公司
for your home and personal belongings.
因为哥斯拉不会在乎你们的希望和梦想
Because Godzilla may not care about your hopes and dreams,
但巨人保险在乎
but Gargantua does.
好的各位 巨兽的真相的听众朋友
Okay, Titan truthers!
在今天的节目里
Oh, we have got a lot…
我们要揭开很多秘密
to unpack on today's show.
正在录节目呢 快走开
Recording in progress, go away!
对 我只是想告诉大家
Uh, yes. I just want to let everyone know
其实根本没有…
that there is no…
我要宰了这人
I'm gonna kill…
真是服了 干嘛
Unbelievable! What?
伯尼
Hi, Bernie.
艾琳·安德鲁斯 我们在香港见过
Ilene Andrews, we met in Hong Kong.
对 对对对
Oh. Oh. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
香港 那是很久之前的事了
Hong Kong. Yeah, that was so long ago.
天啊 是的
So, no, God, uh, yeah.
我之前头发长一些
That was when my hair was longer.
你之前 你剪短了头发
You cut your hair.
还挑染了 不错
Highlights too, it's nice.
我在想 能不能请你帮个忙
I was wondering if I could get your help with something.
我
Me?
好 好 行
Uh, sure.
没问题 进来吧 安德鲁斯博士
Sure, yeah. Of course, yeah. Come on in, Doctor Andrews.
好的
Okay.
好
Yeah.
沿着走廊走 然后左拐 好的
Just straight down that hall there. To the left. Okay.
（谢绝上门推销 别找借口）
坐吧
Have a seat.
我能帮你点什么呢
What can I help you with?
（西班牙语）随意一点 别拘束
You know, mi casa es su home.
好 是这样
Okay, so.
看右边的序列
The sequence on the right,
这个信号一直在干扰地心空洞里的设备
this is a signal that's been interfering with our equipment in Hollow Earth.
好的 然后…
Okay. And, uh…
这些画 是我女儿吉雅画出来的
And these are drawings by my daughter, Jia.
你可能会觉得我精神不正常
And you're gonna think that I'm completely insane.
不 中间部分的图案一模一样
No, the patterns are the same in the middle section.
对 就是这样
Yes. Exactly.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看 我们的分析员毫无头绪
Look, our analysts, they don't know what to make of this.
还一直兜圈子 说是
They're talking in circles,
无线电干扰 纯属巧合 但我…
they're saying "radio interference, " "coincidence, " but I…
我知道你的思维异于常人
I know that you think outside of the box.
我实在不知道该找谁了
I didn't know who else to turn to.
他们派你来 是因为…
And they sent you here because…?
不 没人派我来 是我自己
No, no one sent me. I came here on my…
听着 这也太讽刺了
You know, that's what's ironic.
帝王组织不肯承认我在
You know, Monarch wouldn't confirm
摧毁机械哥斯拉过程中的作用
my crucial part in taking down Mechagodzilla,
害我损失了几千
which cost me thousands of…
几百名个人播客的粉丝
hundreds of subscribers on my blog.
我想问 还有喷子
Oh, and the trolls…
网上那些喷子
the trolls online, they question
我不管发什么 他们都会喷
every single thing that I put up.
尤其是 有这么个喷子
Especially this one troll.
网名叫基多拉斯坦64 你听说过吗
This one troll named ghidorastan64. You ever heard of him?
没有 我从来没有
No, I don't think I have.
很好 因为他就是个人渣
Great, because he's a trash bag, okay?
我这次来是为了 我敢说
I'm more qualified than half of those people
我比你一半的手下都更有资质
that you have working over there.
我比帝王组织的任何人
I knew what Godzilla was going to do
都更早知道 哥斯拉要…
before anybody at Monarch said…
所以我才来找你 伯尼
Which is why I am here, Bernie.
我来找你了 好吗
I am here. Okay?
你能不能帮帮我
Can you help me or not?
看情况
That depends.
你是帝心站的新老大吗
Are you the new boss down at the Mess?
什么站
The what?
帝王组织地心空洞观测站 帝心站
The Monarch Hollow Earth Station. The MHES, the Mess.
没人这么说
Yeah, nobody calls it that.
我负责金刚研究部 但…
I run the Kong research division but…
严格来说 整体管理是由汉普顿主任负责的
technically Director Hampton is in charge of general operations.
但她没有一个可以和金刚交流的孩子
Well, Director Hampton doesn't have a kid who can talk to Kong.
你想去地心空洞
You want to go to Hollow Earth.
没用我自己说 太好了
I'm so glad I didn't have to say it.
- 我还以为你不会邀请我呢 - 不
- I thought you were never gonna ask - No,
我不是在邀请你 我确实需要证据
I'm not asking. but I really do need proof.
可以帮我提升播客的可信度
I mean, that would help me with my bona fides for my blog.
我知道 你一定会帮我实现愿望的
And I knew that you would be the person to help me do that.
好吧 真能去的话 这也不太可能
Okay. Well, if this happens, and that is a big if, then Monarch would need
帝王组织会要你所有作品的最终剪辑权
then Monarch would need, you know, whatever you guys call it. Final cut on anything in…
（帝王组织紧急警报）
不好意思 最终剪辑权 不 不 不
Whoa. I'm sorry, final cut? No, no, no.
（巨兽警报 哥斯拉的生命体征指数飙升 请求指示）
这会毁掉我报道的可信度 优秀的记录者
You know, that will destroy my journalistic integrity.
该死
Shit.
我是不会交出最终剪辑权的
No really true, good documentarian gives final cut.
但我可以让你当制片人
I could make you a producer.
好吧 行 最终剪辑权归你们了
Okay, okay! Fine! Final cut! Final cut! Fine!
听着 我女儿出了点问题
Look, something is happening to my daughter,
我完全不知道该怎么解决
and I have no idea how to fix it.
只要你能帮我
You work out what's going on,
我可以满足你的任何要求 这样行吗
and I will get you anything that you want, okay?
我向你保证
That is a promise.
这个承诺有点空泛
Well, anything is a lot,
但是 但是很大方 但我…
but that's very generous, but I…
我们得走了 就现在
And we have to go. Right now.
什么
What?
哥斯拉又开始活动了
Godzilla is on the move again.
好了 听我说 如果哥斯拉活动了
Okay, listen to me.
那它一定是感受到了威胁
If Godzilla's on the move, he senses a threat coming.
但具体的我们还不清楚
We don't know what it is.
你不担心吗
And you're not concerned?
我们当然担心 参议员
Of course we're concerned, Senator.
所以我们一直在监测全局
That's why we're monitoring the situation.
如果监测到哥斯拉朝金刚
Monitor the fact that if Godzilla heads…
怎么了 你先 有一点可以确定
What is it? You just… And I am telling you
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem!
参议员…
Senator…
金刚不会离开地心空洞
that Kong doesn't leave Hollow Earth.
所以哥斯拉也就没有理由 还击
Which is why Godzilla has no reason to retaliate.
它怎么上来了
What's he doing up here?
不知道啊
No idea.
哥斯拉知道了吗
Well, does Godzilla know?
现在还不确定
Not that we can tell.
它迟早会知道的
Yeah, well, it's only a matter of time.
如果哥斯拉开始往这边来了该怎么办
And what happens if Godzilla starts heading this way?
那我们只能拼命跑了
Then we all run like hell.
起来 快跟上 快 我们走
Get up, let's go! Keep it up. Come on. Let's go.
它受伤了
镇静剂已就位
Sedatives in place.
好了 好消息是 只是牙齿发炎
All right, the good news is it's just an infected tooth.
幸运的是 你们找来了最好的医生
But luckily, you've come to the best doctor in town.
有我在
♪ I gotcha ♪
好了 金刚完全睡过去了 生命体征稳定
All right, Kong sedation at a 100%. Vitals stable.
特雷普 你现在可以下去换掉它的坏牙了
Trapper, you are clear to swap the damaged tooth with replacement.
特雷普已着陆
Touchdown, Trapper.
伙计 早餐吃什么了
Whoa. Fella. What'd you have for breakfast?
怎么样
All right?
好了 这颗烂牙要出来了
Yeah, this sucker's ready to come out.
好的 开始拔
All right, let's roll!
你来了
There she is.
特雷普 谢谢你这么快赶过来
Trapper. Thanks for getting down here so fast.
干得不错
Nice work.
乐意为您效劳
You are most welcome.
爬进90米高的巨猿嘴里可是件稀罕事 对吧
It's not every day you get to climb inside a 300-foot ape's mouth, is it?
是啊
Yeah.
你确定那东西够坚硬
And you're sure it's gonna be strong enough?
那颗牙吗 对
The tooth? Yeah.
和汽车隔热板用的是同一种聚合物复合材料
That's the same polymer composite they use on the vehicle heat shields.
它都能咬断埃菲尔铁塔了
He could chomp through the Eiffel Tower with that thing.
要是哥斯拉知道它在这里 牙再硬也没用
Well, good teeth aren't gonna help if Godzilla senses that he's up here.
但是…
Well…
让泰坦巨兽牙疼多不像话
You can't have a Titan with a toothache, can you?
是啊
No.
别担心 它可能会头晕个几小时
Don't worry. Couple of hours he might be a bit groggy,
但不影响回到地下
but he'll be good to go back down.
我最开始听说你要当兽医时 心想
You know, when I first heard that you were gonna be a vet
不 那对特雷普来说太无聊了
I thought no. That is way too boring for Trapper.
结果你成了全世界最另类的兽医
Then you go and become the weirdest vet in the world.
是啊 我和杜立德医生一样厉害
Yeah, it's basically me and Doctor Dolittle.
只是我的病人个头更大
Except my animals are bigger.
我以为 终于有人让他成熟了
I thought finally, someone has made him grow up.
没有
Nope.
大学里有人试过 但…
Someone tried that back in college, but…
没有成功
didn't really work.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
对 她当时和我说
Yeah, what was it she said to me?
特雷普 你这人 太吊儿郎当了
"Trapper, you are not a serious person."
她是个聪明人呢
Oh, she sounds very smart.
确实
Yeah,
她有个博士学位
ish. She got a PhD.
其实是两个
Two, actually.
她还好吗
How's the kid doing?
你知道的 她很挣扎
You know. Struggling.
在努力适应这个世界
Trying to find her place in the world.
我能理解
Yeah, I know how that goes.
别担心 她没事的
Don't worry, she'll be all right.
她有个好妈妈
She got a good mum.
好好休息
你会好起来的
你看起来状态不错
安德鲁斯博士
Doctor Andrews.
你的…
Your…
客人一直在找你
guest has been asking for you.
你可千万别误会我啊
Please don't take this the wrong way,
我想说
but can I just say,
你的研究资料库里面有很多明显的疏漏
that your research library has many glaring omissions.
害得我找了好几个贴吧好友帮忙
I had to call in some serious favors from my Discord chat.
他们不 伯尼 你有发现吗
They were not… Bernie, do you have something?
有 我有发现 我确实有发现
Yes, I've got something. I do have something.
我们发现你们监测到的信号
Whatever signal you guys are picking up,
一直在以类似的模式不断地重复
okay, we have seen similar patterns repeating over time.
每个峰值都对应一次泰坦巨兽事件
And each spike corresponds with a specific Titan event.
能帮我拿一下吗 多谢
Can you hold this, please? Thank you so much.
好的 看看这个
Okay, check this out.
瞧见没
See this?
王者基多拉 首次与哥斯拉相遇
King Ghidorah, huh? First encounter with Godzilla.
这里 发现了骷髅岛
Here, uh, discovery of Skull Island.
所以 你是说这些信号不是无缘无故形成的
All right. So what you're saying is that these signals aren't just random patterns.
对 应该是这样
Yeah, it seems that way, yes.
哥斯拉也收到了
And Godzilla's picking up on it?
不止如此 我查看了
Oh, I can do you one better. Now, look,
每个波形图中的相似点
I've looked at points of similarities
然后与信号进行了对比
in each wave form and I compared them to that pattern, and…
伯尼 你想说什么
Bernie, what are you saying?
这是一种求救信号
It's a distress call!
是求救信号 用心理能量发出的
It's a distress call. A psychic energy SOS.
如果你女儿看到了这些符号
Now, if your daughter is seeing these symbols,
就说明下面有东西 正在呼救
then something down there is calling for help.
普通的声波传播这么远后 音质一定会衰减
Regular soundwaves, they can't propagate this far without decay. This?
我们从来没遇到过这种信号
This is something that we have never encountered.
而且它还在变强
And it's getting stronger.
有理论支持吗
You got a working theory?
一种外星的心灵感应语言
Yeah, telepathic alien language.
是某种求救信号
It's some sort of distress signal.
信号 什么发的
Signal? From what?
可能是人发出的
Or from who.
不管怎样 这是哥斯拉活跃的原因
Well, whatever it is, this is why Godzilla's on the move?
现在还不能确定 但应该是这样
We can't say for sure. But it seems that way.
好吧 我们得尽快搞清楚
Well, we have to figure this out fast.
危险已经迫在眉睫了
The wolves are already at our door.
政府一直在找各种借口 企图接手地心空洞
The government has been looking for an excuse to take over Hollow Earth operations.
各大企业也都虎视眈眈
And the corporations are licking their chops.
也难怪 谁不想除掉这些怪兽 再发笔横财
Yeah, because who wants to be rich and get rid of all the monsters?
这可不是什么好事 对吧
I mean, that'd be terrible, right?
我们最好赶在政府之前找到信号源
We'd better find the source before D.C. gets wind of this.
好吧
Okay.
我要让你全权负责这次行动 带上几个人
I'm giving you full operational oversight.
米凯尔 开快点 千万别死人
Take a small team. Mikael, make it fast and don't let anyone die.
我们天黑之前就能回来
We'll be in and out of there before nightfall.
你 你要不要一起去？
You, uh, you feel like going for a ride?
恭敬不如从命
Thought you'd never ask.
各部门人员请注意
Attention, all hands.
五分钟后发射地飞3号 请做好准备
Prepare HEAV three for Hollow Earth launch in T minus five minutes.
地心空洞前哨站没有任何回应
There's no response from the Hollow Earth outpost.
应该是无线电坏了
Their radios must be down.
那我们先去那里
Well, then that's our first stop.
收到
Copy that.
我想跟你一起去
我说什么都不想让你去 下面太危险了
有东西在召唤我
「你应该在我身边 我也应该在你身边」
你要用我的话反驳我？
不是吧？
再说了 你或许会需要我跟金刚交流
都打起精神来 各位
All right, wakey wakey, everyone.
它醒了
Kong's up.
你要时刻在我身边
安德鲁斯博士
Hey. Hey! Doctor Andrews.
我们明明说好了的
Hey. Come on, we had a deal!
我们不是去观光 是去执行侦查任务
Bernie, this isn't sightseeing. It's a reconnaissance mission.
等一下 我明白了
So, I see how it is.
要用我的时候就说
When you need something, it's all
你真聪明 伯尼 你这么有本事 伯尼
"you're so smart, Bernie, you're so capable, Bernie,
我一定会订阅你的播客 伯尼
"I'll subscribe to your Titan blog, Bernie, "
等我一弄完 你就把我丢一边了
and when I deliver it, you toss me aside.
好吧 其实 可能会有危险
Okay, look. This could be dangerous.
拜托 危险再大 我也不怕
Come on. I'm no stranger to danger.
我不是故意押韵的
I didn't mean to rhyme that time.
你欠我人情好不好 我破解了这个呢
Look, you owe me. Okay? I helped crack this thing.
我们可以像上次那样拯救世界 还记得吗
This could be like last time, when we saved the world. Remember?
米凯尔
Mikael?
再准备一个座位
Yeah. Prep a seat for one more.
谢谢安德鲁斯博士 你一定不会失望的
Thank you, Doctor Andrews! You will not regret it.
你在逗我吧
You're kidding, right?
我是新来的 你好
I'm the plus one. Hello.
系统上线
Systems online.
我们上线了
We're online.
要去地心空洞了
We are going to Hollow Earth.
我要去地心空洞了
I am going to Hollow Earth.
天啊 我没做梦吧
Oh, my God. What am I doing?
坐地飞有什么 我需要了解的注意事项吗
So, is there, like, a in-flight briefing that I should know about? You know…
对 有的
Yeah, there is.
他比较 这里没有降落伞
He's very… There's no parachutes,
也没有什么漂浮装置
no flotation devices,
要是敢碰屏幕 手就废了
you touch any of this stuff, you lose your hand,
你要是死
and if you die,
可别死在我的舱里
make sure it's outside my vehicle.
说得好
Good briefing.
说得妙
Great briefing.
你别怪米凯尔 他是爱之深责之切
Don't take Mikael too personally. Aggression is his love language.
好了 米凯尔 我们出发吧
All right, Mikael. Let's punch it.
地飞1号 可以起飞
HEAV one, you are clear for launch.
那就来吧
Let's do this.
你最好别把舌头咽下去
Just try not to swallow your tongue.
什么
What?
最好别把舌头咽下去
Try not to swallow my tongue
我都不知道那是什么意思
I don't exactly know what that means.
基地呼叫地飞 准备就绪
Base to HEAV, you're clear for entry.
安德鲁斯博士 请倒计时
On your count, Doctor Andrews
- 三 - 出发
- Three. - All right, let's go.
- 二 - 等等 我没准备好
- Two. - I'm not ready.
- 一 - 天啊
- And one. - Oh, my God!
我要被…
I'm…
晃成水了
turning into water.
飞行系统已上线 系统已稳定
Flight systems active. Systems stabilized.
系统正常 博士
Systems stabilized. Doc.
大家怎么样
How's everyone doing?
- 没事吧 - 好极了
- You all right? - Never better.
好的
Yeah?
伯尼 怎么样
Bernie, you good?
挺好
Nice one.
看来金刚要回家
Looks like Kong is headed home.
离前哨站还有多远
How far to the outpost?
一百公里 他们还是没有回应
Hundred klicks. They're still not answering comms.
近距离警报
Proximity alert.
9点钟方向有掠食鸟
Predators, nine o'clock.
哪里 什么
Where? What?
是彩翼鸟 米凯尔 它们叫彩翼鸟
Those are vertacines, Mikael. They're called vertacines.
对我们有威胁吗
Um, are they a problem?
没事 完全无害
No. They're totally harmless.
除非把它们惹恼了
Unless you get them riled up,
它们就会发射生物电磁闪电攻击你
and then they pack about a lightning bolt worth of bioelectricity.
掠食者懂得保持距离
Predators know to stay well away.
所以 如果能有酷炫的仿生学迷彩外观
Which makes them the perfect chaperone
它们会是完美的护卫队
if you happen to have a cool biomimicry camouflage.
而我们真的有
Which we do.
什么情况
Talk to me.
情况不妙
It's not good.
哥斯拉刚刚在法国登陆了
Godzilla just made landfall in France.
地面小队在它五公里之外
Ground team is five klicks out.
法国 蒙塔尼亚克
地面小队呼叫帝王组织…
…我们在接近哥斯拉所在位置
有画面了
We got picture.
天啊 这是一个核设施
Oh, my God. It's a nuclear facility.
核反应堆被破坏了！
整个区域都受到了核辐射！
快撤退 撤退！
大气辐射量在降低
Atmospheric radiation levels
它在吸收核辐射
are dropping. He's absorbing it.
知道了 它在补充能量
Okay, he's charging for something.
哥斯拉吸收了大量核辐射
Godzilla consumed a huge amount of radiation.
它肯定在为什么做准备
He is clearly preparing for something…
超出范围
Out of range.
可恶
Damn it.
马上到达1号前哨站
We're coming up on Outpost One.
天啊
Oh, God.
这看起来可不太妙啊
Oh, well, now. That doesn't look good now, does it?
能看到吗 博士
You seeing this, Doc?
我看到了
Yeah. Yeah, I'm seeing it.
没有热感信号
Well, there's no heat signatures.
恐怕全死光了
So much for survivors.
放尊重点 他们也有家人
God, have some respect. These people had families.
是什么东西干的
What could have done this?
我不明白
I don't understand,
这个前哨站这么多年都安然无恙
we've had this outpost for years without incident.
怎么现在被毁了呢
So, why attack now?
哪里变了
What changed?
博士 这里有个摄像机
Hey, Doc. There's a camera here.
你觉得能 调出什么画面吗
You reckon you can pull any footage off of that?
不是吧
Oh, shit.
是不是金刚干的
You think Kong did that?
不 不是它 是别的东西
No, that's not Kong. That's something else.
对 我们
Yeah.
赶紧走吧 趁着那个东西还没回来
Let's get off the ground before that something else comes back.
我们走吧 快点
Saddle up. Let's hustle.
地下 未知区域
那东西上面有什么线索吗
Are you getting anything off that thing?
我就是…
Yeah, I'm just…
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What?
给
Here.
你自己看
Take a look.
看着像是一头猿 但这不可能
It looks like an ape. But that's impossible.
那是什么鬼玩意儿
What the bloody hell is that?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
不 米凯尔 米凯尔
No! Mikael! Mikael!
我在处理呢 给力点…
I'm working on it! Come on, you…
天啊 好吧 好吧 好吧
God! Okay, okay, okay!
什么情况 米凯尔
The hell was that, Mikael?
淡定 淡定
Calm down. Calm down.
一定是因为那个信号
It must've been the signal.
前哨站受到了同样的电子干扰
The same electrical disturbances were happening at the outpost.
飞行系统已稳定
信号越来越强了
是吗
是从那一带发出来的
你确定…？
她说是从山脊那边发出来的
She says it's coming from that ridge point.
那我们过去看看吧
Well, let's take a look.
我尽量靠得近一些
I'll get as close as I can.
地心空洞
The Hollow Earth.
一个没有被人类影响过的世界
A world untouched by mankind.
当年尼尔·阿姆斯特朗踏上外星表面的时候
Is this how Neil Armstrong felt
就是这种感受吗
when he stepped on alien soil?
这是
Is this
我个人的一小步 却是人类的一大步…
one small step for me, and one giant leap for…
- 你跟谁说话呢 - 你搞笑呢吧
- Who are you talking to? - Are you kidding me?
没看到镜头吗
Right down the lens?
我拍纪录片呢 你得自然点
It's a documentary. You wanna be natural.
往前走 你就往前走
Just walk, if you just walk. All right, just keep…
对 好 第二条
Yeah, just… Okay. Take two.
地心空洞 一个…
The Hollow Earth. A world…
好了 各位
All right, guys.
你们说的那道山脊在正前方大约3.2公里以外
That ridge you pointed out is about two miles straight ahead.
我怕是要被活活吃掉了
I'm getting eaten alive out here.
瞧瞧
Oh, look at that.
我的血肯定也好喝
I must be tasty too.
弄死它
Kill it.
只有母蚊子才吸血
Only female mosquitos drink blood.
这样它们才能产卵
So they can grow their eggs.
它比我更需要血
She needs it more than me.
等一下
Wait.
怎么了
What?
怎么不走了
What's the holdup?
不能走这边
Not this way.
什么 为什么
What? Why?
我们得绕开这里 这里不对劲
Yeah, we gotta take a detour. There's something here.
这里指的是哪里？
Where, here?
你是说这里？
Like here, here?
不 仪器什么都没感应到
Nah. I'm not picking anything up.
不 这里味儿不对
No. Something doesn't smell right,
不只是你身上的味儿 米凯尔
and it's not just you, Mikael.
闻到了吗 像是…
Can you smell that? It's like…
像腐肉的气味
rotting flesh.
可能上风地带有动物尸体吧 继续前进
It's probably just a carcass upwind. We keep moving.
米凯尔 等一下
Mikael, hold up.
听着 伙计
Listen, pal. I'm gonna trust
我更相信自己先进的热感仪
my state of the art thermal over your
而不是你那不着调的嬉皮士第六感
Ace Ventura hippie-dippie sixth sense
不论什么时候
all day long.
听见没
You got me?
没有必要骂人吧 我们就是…
There's no need to call people names. We're just…
至于你 怪胎
Hey. And as for you, freak show,
你要是不给我闭嘴
if you don't shut it,
我就用那台摄像机好好招呼你的屁股
I'm gonna take that camera, I'm gonna shove it right up your arse.
我说了算
I'm in charge,
继续前进
we move.
为什么不听更冷静的人的意见呢 米凯尔
Why don't we just listen to somebody calmer?
因为你感觉到 都说了 我说了算
I said I'm in charge.
我说了算
I'm in charge!
快跑
Run!
他被树吃了
It was a tree.
- 等一下 等一下 - 他被树吃了
- Wait, wait, wait. - It was a tree!
应该没事了 应该没事了
We should be all right. We should be all right.
那种东西跑不了这么远
Those things don't reach that far.
他被树给吃掉了
He was just eaten by a tree.
你在干什么 博士
What you doing, Doc?
尝试呼叫基地 准备撤离
I'm trying to call the Base for extraction.
真的 他前一秒还在那里
It's just, one minute he was there, right?
就杵在我面前 然后那裸树 突然就
He was right in my face. And then, a tree!
我懂 兄弟 我懂 这事很沉重
Outta nowhere! I know, man. I know. That's heavy.
但自然界就是这样
But that's the natural world, man.
「爪牙染满了血」
"Red in tooth and claw."
丁尼生
Tennyson.
你刚眼看着一个活人
You just watched a man
被树雕怪吃了 还有心情引用丁尼生的诗
get devoured by a topiary nightmare, and you want to quote Tennyson?
在这地底下
Down here?
是啊 兄弟
Yeah. Yeah, man.
他写的是事实
He knew all about it.
让爱紧抓住悲痛 兄弟 来
"Let love clasp grief, " man. Come here.
我们人类总以为自己已经不在食物链里了
You know, humans, we think we took ourselves off the food chain,
但是…
but…
也许
maybe
也许泰坦巨兽就是来提醒我们的
maybe the Titans are here to remind us.
我觉得你这个人挺有毛病的
I think that there is something seriously wrong with you.
- 好吧 - 好的
- Okay. - Mm-kay. - Okay.
联络不上
It's not working.
我们最好继续
We better move on.
回头再哀悼
We'll mourn later.
吉雅 走了
Jia. Come on.
走吧 兄弟
Come on, bud.
可是 他被一棵树吃了
He was eaten by a tree.
我可不想那么死掉
I don't… I don't want to die like that.
我不想被树吃
Not by a tree.
西班牙 加的斯
塔台 我们没法再靠近了
Tower, we can't get any closer than this.
哥斯拉身上带着辐射 体温很高
Godzilla's burning hot with radiation.
有东西把它给惹恼了 它要往那里赶
Whatever he's headed for has him really pissed off.
基地呼叫15A潜艇 完毕
This is Base calling Fifteen Alpha, over.
这里是15A
Fifteen Alpha responding.
哥斯拉目前的行动轨迹表明
Godzilla's current trajectory is showing
它正在前往北冰洋
him heading towards the Arctic Ocean.
那片区域都有哪些巨兽
What Titans are in the area?
（克维托亚岛）
（克维托亚岛 侦测到泰坦巨兽019）
看来它是冲提亚马特去的
Looks like he's hunting Tiamat.
机密文件324
Classified file three two four.
泰坦巨兽提亚马特 19号巨兽
Titanus Tiamat. Titan nineteen.
极具攻击性 有领地意识
Extremely aggressive, territorial.
身上覆有锋利的鳞片
Weaponizing her body
令它如虎添翼
of razor-sharp scales…
提亚马特的北极巢穴
Tiamat's Arctic lair
位于电磁太阳风的直接路径上
sits in the direct path of electromagnetically charged solar winds,
也因此成为了地球上最大的能源储备库
making it the largest stockpile of energy on Earth.
如果哥斯拉打倒了提亚马特
If Godzilla takes down Tiamat,
就会进行超级充能
he'll supercharge.
是遗迹
It's ruins.
人类文明？
Human civilization?
在这里吗
Down here?
这是我们族人的符号！
是的
Yeah.
这些刻文的年头
The markings are older than the ones
比骷髅岛上那些早了很多个世纪
on Skull Island. Centuries older.
但这座建筑和伊维族的建筑一致
But the architecture is consistent with the Iwi.
他们怎么了？
真是不可思议
Oh, this is remarkable.
这里很奇怪
Now, that's weird.
这些台阶上没有苔藓
There's no moss on these ones.
你好
Hello.
摩斯拉
Mothra.
地心空洞的 怪兽女王
Queen of the monsters. In Hollow Earth.
它的起源时间一定比我们想象的要久远
Her lineage must go back further than we thought.
这里曾经是一座神庙…
…是祭拜的场所
对
Yeah.
别 别 别
No, no, no.
这是什么
What is that? Whoa!
看着像是灌溉系统
It's like some kind of a irrigation system.
只不过它是问世最早的
Only this predates everything
什么美索不达米亚文明 利莫里亚文明
Mesopotamians, the Lemurians…
他们这里才是最早的
I mean, these guys were the first, man!
吉雅 等一下
Jia.
水还在往前流呢
It just keeps going.
等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
抱歉
Oh. Sorry.
我去…
Oh, whoa. What the…
这趟真是值了
Now, that is a trip.
惊世大发现 你们看
Great Mulder and Scully, look at that.
是什么创造了它呢
What could have created this?
远古外星宇航员
Ancient alien astronauts.
你们来看这个
Look at this here.
水在下面流
The water's running underneath.
而这个是有机的
And this is organic.
嗯
Yeah.
像是什么生物电站
Some kind of bioelectric hub.
像一层伪装
It's like camouflage.
她是该这么干吗
Should she be doing that?
是不是不该这么干啊
She shouldn't be doing that, right? Should she…?
跟我梦里的一样
这肯定就是信号源了
This must be the source of the signal.
我们可得好好瞧瞧
Oh, we've gotta check this out.
是啊
Yeah.
好了 走吧 走吧
Okay. Go, go, go. Go.
北冰洋 提亚玛特的领地
15A报告基地
Fifteen Alpha reporting to base.
我们正在进入提亚马特的领地
We're entering Tiamat's domain,
情况有些异常
but something is off.
提亚马特的能量把我们的雷达弄失真了
Tiamat's energy is distorting our radar.
现在看不到哥斯拉
We don't have a visual on Godzilla.
向前行进
Take us forward, silent running…
- 静音潜航 - 是 长官
- silent running… - Yes, sir.
航速五节
five knots.
求救 快撤出来
Mayday! Get that out!
快撤出来
Get that out!
- 我需要状态报告 - 对
- I need a status report! - That's right.
它进了提亚马特的巢穴
He's gone to Tiamat's lair.
等一下 等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
她说什么
Wait, what did she say?
她说这里不只有我们
She says we're not alone.
看吧 我就知道
See? I knew it.
我就觉得这里有东西
I knew I felt something.
尽管来吧
Come on, then.
快走
Go.
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 天啊 天啊 - 我马上收 我马上收
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God. - It's going away. It's going away.
好了
Okay.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
这是？
What?
这是一个在地心空洞里保存完好的伊维文明
It's an entire Iwi civilization, protected within Hollow Earth.
看样子 这些建筑都是用
These structures, they look like they've been
巨大的石英晶体雕凿而成的
carved from some enormous quartz crystal.
那肯定是他们的能量源
That must be their energy source.
我感受到能量了 但你控制下情绪好吗
I'm feeling the energy, but let's just keep it together, all right?
我能感知他们的想法
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
那是 一个没有被记录在案的涡旋
It's an undocumented vortex.
看样子是有好几个
Looks like several of them, actually.
通往地表的通道 可能会通在
Routes to the surface.
地球上的任何地方
These could lead all over the Earth.
太神奇了
Oh, wow. That's incredible.
要和他们用眼神交流 这样才礼貌
You should make eye contact with them. It's considered polite.
那个 这样弄得我很不自在
Yeah, this is not working for me.
他们是怎么沟通的
How are they communicating?
通过心灵感应
Telepathically.
好
Okay.
不 不行 不行
No, I, no, no, no.
- 你不能带她走 - 感觉她要带她去
- You can't take her. - I think she's taking her to the…
那让我去吧 我们不反抗
Well, let me come! Hey! Hey! Hey!
- 我们不反抗 - 等一下 等一下
- Hold on, okay, we're not resisting. - Wait, wait, wait.
别这样 让我去
Don't do this, let me go
我不知道她要带她去哪里
I don't know where she's taking her! Hey!
没事的
好吧
Okay.
- 好了 走吧 - 走 走 好
- Okay, come on. Okay. - Let's go, let's go.
我能不能？
Can I?
谢谢
Thank you.
这里就是信号源
我知道
Of course.
她说什么 博士
What's she saying, Doc?
那个我们一直在追踪的信号 其实…
The beacon that we've been following, it's…
其实是伊维人在呼救
It's the Iwi calling for help.
天啊
Oh. Whoa.
等一下 他们发了求救信号
So, wait. They send out this SOS,
那然后呢
and then what?
哥斯拉听到了吗
Godzilla hears it?
对
Yeah.
他们唤醒了它
They woke him up.
发求救信号干什么
An SOS for what?
他们已经活在一个噩梦般的怪兽环境里了
They already live in a nightmare monster hellscape.
还有什么能吓到他们
What could possibly scare them?
你说的话她都听得懂
Hey. She can understand everything that you say.
她懂我的话？
She understands me?
这下好了
Oh, good.
那个 这种噩梦般的怪兽环境呢
And a nightmare monster hellscape
是一个生养子女的好地方
is a wonderful place to raise a family.
这个房间里都是伊维人的记录
This whole room is covered in Iwi script.
上面说
It says that
在一开始 地心空洞
in the beginning, Hollow Earth
曾与地表世界和谐共处
lived in harmony with the surface world.
泰坦巨兽是自然界的守护者
The Titans were the guardians of nature
而巨猿
and the Great Apes
则是成为了整个人类族群的守护者
became the protectors of humanity.
但一股巨大的邪恶力量威胁到了和平
But a great evil threatened the peace.
一头强大而残暴的猿
A powerful and ruthless ape
迫切想要征服地表世界
desperate to conquer the surface world,
它带领自己的部落开了战
led his tribe into war
对手就是伊维族所说的…
against the one they call…
吞星怪兽
The Monster Who Ate a Star.
哥斯拉
Godzilla.
这还没完
There's more.
哥斯拉险些在与众猿的战斗中丧命
The war with the Apes nearly destroyed Godzilla.
但在一场大战之后
But after a great battle,
它把众猿囚禁在了
he imprisoned the apes
地心空洞的一片炽热之地里
in a fiery realm of Hollow Earth.
那个冒牌的猿中王者仍然一心想要上地表
Their false king remains obsessed with reaching the surface.
伊维人叫它…
The Iwi call him the…
刀疤王
Skar King.
困在地下的刀疤王
Trapped within their subterranean realm,
驯服了一个可怕的帮手
the Skar King harnessed a terrible power.
远古泰坦巨兽 雪魔
The ancient Titan, Shimo.
它用痛苦控制雪魔
He controls her with pain.
雪魔的力量曾在上一个冰期威震整个地球
Her power covered the Earth in the last ice age.
我们把金刚送了下来
We brought Kong down here.
它一直在寻找同类 深入地心空洞
He's been looking for others like himself, going deeper into Hollow Earth
也离那座囚笼越来越近
and getting closer to their prison.
伊维人一定知道金刚迟早会找过去
The Iwi must have known it was just a matter of time,
所以他们一直在呼救
and that's why they've been
这也是哥斯拉要进化的原因
calling for help, and that's why Godzilla's changing.
它在为第三次世界大战做准备
He's gearing up for World War Three.
好吧 可哥斯拉上回勉强捡了条命
Okay, but he barely survived last time.
这次它孤军奋战 又能如何
What's Godzilla gonna do on his own?
它不会孤军奋战的
He won't be on his own.
伊维人认为 在世界末日来临之时
The Iwi believe that at the end of the world,
他们的一个族人会归来
one of their own will return…
并唤醒摩斯拉
and awaken Mothra,
它是伊维族的捍卫者
defender of the Iwi…
也是哥斯拉的古老盟友
and ancient ally of Godzilla.
伊维人相信 他们的救世主
They believe that their savior will be
会是一个来自骷髅岛的伊维人
an Iwi from Skull Island.
她还是个孩子 就要承担这些
That seems like a lot to put on one kid.
帝王组织空中小队呼叫基地
This is Monarch Air Team to Base,
我们在追踪哥斯拉的位置
tracking over Godzilla's location.
我们已经关闭了480公里内的航道
We've closed the shipping lanes within 300 miles.
等离子体读数显示
Plasma readings indicate
它正在吸收里面的所有能量
he's absorbing everything in there.
我刚收养她的时候 发过一个誓
You know, I made a deal with myself when I became a mother.
我这么告诉自己
I said to myself,
不管你今后要牺牲什么 或者是…
I don't care what you have to sacrifice…
放弃什么
what you have to give up,
你都一定要对那个小姑娘好
you will do right by that little girl.
我从来没有想过 我要放弃的会是她
I just never thought that the thing I'd be giving up would be her.
现在还说不好呢
Look, you don't know that.
是吗
Really?
特雷普 我们来这里之前 她说
Trapper, before we came here
自己不属于任何地方
she said that she didn't belong anywhere.
如果这是她想要的生活 我就…
If this is the life that she wants…
不得不放手了
then I have to give her up.
是我犯晕了 还是这里的一切都变轻了
Am I having a funny turn or does everything feel lighter down here?
你先给我蹲下
[Bernie mumbles incoherently]
等一下 等一下 等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
他们这是干什么呢
What are they doing?
那玩意儿肯定沉死了
That must weigh a ton.
对
Yeah.
对 我也不知道他们是怎么做到的
Yeah, see, I don't know how they can do it…
但他们有办法移动金字塔的位置
but somehow they're able to move the pyramids' positions,
从而扰乱这里的地心引力
which disrupts the gravitational pull down here,
他们就是这样让城市运作的
and that's how they run their city.
整个文明都建立在操控地心引力的基础上
An entire civilization built off the manipulation of gravity.
天呢 真希望这是在直播
God, I wish was streaming this live!
你想怎么处理视频 伯尼
What you gonna do with that, Bern?
我知道你在想什么 可是…
Look, I know what you're thinking…
你不懂 明白吗
but you don't understand. Okay?
那些事明明都是我亲身经历或亲眼所见
To have been through what I've been through, seen what I seen
却根本没有人相信
and have absolutely nobody believe you.
这个地方 这个地方真的很特别
This place… This place is special, man.
充满魔力
It's magic.
你觉得 如果你把视频发到网上
How long do you think it'll stay like that
这种状态还能维持多久
if you start posting that about, hmm?
你看看那些与世隔绝的部落或社区
Like, you look at any isolated tribe or community,
有多少能在接触了外界以后留存下来
how many of them urvive contact with the outside world, hmm?
知道吗 我觉得你可捧了
You know I think you're brilliant, don't you?
你已经拯救过一次世界了
You already saved the world once.
这功劳没人抢得走
Can't take that away from you.
能不能再说一遍
Could you say that all again?
最后这一段 我好录下来
The last part, so I have it on footage.
什么
What?
我们一定得去看看那是什么 对吧
Oh, well, we have to find out what that was, right?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
那是一头迷你金刚吗
Is that a mini-Kong?
它们是怎么找到这里的
How did they find this place?
它一定是感知到了吉雅
He must have sensed Jia.
我没有家了
那条胳膊伤得很重
That arm looks bad.
是啊 简直糟透了
Yeah. That's worse than bad.
是冻伤
That's frostbite.
我最好过去看看
I'd better go take a look.
警告 侦测到能量信号改变
Warning, detecting altered energy signature.
（皮肤 肌肉密度增加 体温可调节）
我的天啊 它进化了
Oh, my God. He's changed.
（背鳍 能量储备增加20倍）
我知道 我知道 没有人喜欢牙医
I know, I know. Nobody likes a dentist.
我就过来看看你的胳膊 大块头
Let's get a look at that arm, big guy.
特雷普 它看起来很痛苦
Trapper, he looks really hurt.
是啊 它状况很不好
Yeah, it's not great.
我发现了神经损伤
I'm seeing nerve damage…
还有大面积的组织损伤
significant tissue loss.
那怎么办
So, what are we saying?
只有一条胳膊的话
He's not gonna last
它在这里连一天都活不了
a day down here with only one arm.
对 我们现在还是联系不上地面
Yeah, communication to the surface is still out.
如果我能返回前哨站
If I can get back to the outpost,
说不定那里会有我们用得上的东西
I think there might be some supplies that we can use.
恐怕一块大石膏解决不了问题吧
I don't think a massive cast is gonna solve the problem.
我可没说要去那里弄熟石膏
I wasn't talking plaster of Paris.
我现在主要在想的是…
I'm thinking more along the lines of, uh…
动力室项目
Project Powerhouse.
你是认真的吗
You can't be serious?
我认真极了
Oh, I'm deadly serious.
样机在他们撤资的时候就已经基本做好了
That prototype was almost finished when they pulled the funding.
好吧 那你还待在这里干什么
All right, well, what are you still doing here?
我也爱你 博士
I love you, too, Doc.
动力室项目 这 这具体是个什么项目
Project Powerhouse, what is… what is that, exactly?
机械哥斯拉出现后
After Mechagodzilla,
我们意识到有些威胁就连金刚都对付不了
we realized that there were some threats that even Kong couldn't face.
所以…
So…
我们就开始着手 做些小小的改进
we started working on some minor augmentations.
等一下 是什么样的改进
Wait, what kind of augmentations?
让最强大的泰坦巨兽变得更强
Making one of the strongest Titans
这想法不是很得人心
even stronger didn't go over so well.
所以我们的项目被叫停了
So, we got shut down.
好在样机已经被送到了地心空洞进行测试
Lucky for us, the prototype had already been transported to Hollow Earth for testing.
就存放在1号前哨站的
It's stored
军械库里
in the armory at Outpost One.
（释放载荷）
自动驾驶启动
Autopilot engaged.
这个怎么样
What do you think of that?
这改进可是相当地厉害 特雷普
That's one hell of an augmentation there, Trapper.
我们只给金刚先生用最好的
Only the best for Mr. Kong.
好了 就要开始了
All right, it's ready to go.
这些注射药物应该能有效治疗冻伤
Those injections should heal the frostbite up nicely.
很好 起效了
All right, there he goes.
它动了
He's moving.
你可以的
You got this.
这玩意儿有点粗糙 但应该也不会掉
Look, it's a bit rough and ready, but it should hold.
挺好 看着挺好 特雷普
It's good. It looks good, Trapper.
太好了
Damn good.
- 来看看效果 - 好
- Here we go. - Yeah.
金刚要么会特别喜欢它
He's either gonna love it
要么会用牙把它扯掉
or he's gonna rip it off with his teeth.
感觉金刚喜欢它
I think he loves it!
是不是？
Yeah?
刀疤王
Skar King.
你跟它说什么了
Hey, hey! What did you tell him?
我说 我们需要帮助
它要去哪里
Where's he going?
哥斯拉是不会下来的 除非金刚带它来
Godzilla won't come down here unless Kong brings him.
好吧 它们上次碰面的时候
Okay, the last time those two met up
金刚差点没命了
it was almost the end of Kong.
它在冒很大的风险
He is taking a hell of a risk.
如果金刚入侵它的领地
If Kong invades his turf,
可能会引发战争
could start a war.
是啊 简直是在自投罗网
Yeah, that's a suicide mission.
但如果金刚能把哥斯拉带到这里来
But if Kong draws Godzilla down here…
它们就可以在地心空洞联手抗敌
they can make their stand in Hollow Earth
那样的话
and then there's a chance that
哥斯拉就有机会阻止刀疤王和雪魔前往地表
Godzilla can stop Skar King and Shimo from reaching the surface.
埃及 开罗
快看
快看那里
直布罗陀
话说 真的确定吉雅能把这事给办成吗
We are absolutely certain that she can pull this off, right?
她就是因为这个才被召唤来的
It's why Jia was called here.
只有一个来自骷髅岛的伊维人
Only an Iwi from Skull Island can awaken Mothra.
可以唤醒摩斯拉 而摩斯拉
And Mothra is the key to Godzilla
正是让哥斯拉保护这里
protecting this place,
保护通往地表通道的关键
and its pathways to the surface.
她不会有事的 她不会有事的
She's gonna be all right. She's gonna be all right.
她在让村民们撤离
Hey, she's evacuating the villagers.
重力 重力
Gravity! Gravity!
金字塔和重力 我明白了 这下明白了
The pyramids and gravity. Yeah, I got it! I got it now!
- 路上跟我解释 - 快走 快走
- Tell me on the way. - Come on, come on!
既然我们纯粹是在碰运气
While we are throwing random shit at the wall,
那我能不能开着地飞去 搬点救兵
permission to take the HEAV? Rally some reinforcements.
去地面上吗 不行 没时间了
To the surface? No, there's no time.
不 我的想法可离谱多了
No, this idea's way weirder than that.
好了 我们在金字塔下面了
All right, we're underneath the pyramids.
解释一下吧
Now what?
重力
Gravity.
伊维族的技术
Iwi technology.
发生化学反应后
With the chemical reaction,
这种液态金属会形成一种工程机制
this liquid metal becomes an engineering mechanism
推动这两座电磁金字塔聚合到一起
forcing the two electromagnetic pyramids
产生一道反重力冲击波
together, causing an anti-gravity shock wave.
但它只能维持几分钟 或许会更短
But only for a few minutes. Or maybe less.
这样可以不让那些东西靠近传送口
Which should keep those things from the portals.
在那之后 所有在上面的东西
After that, everything that is up
都会砸下来
will come crashing down.
它们来了
They're here.
我们赶不上了 来不及了
We're not gonna make it. There's not enough time.
得想办法拖住它们
We need something to slow them down.
是啊 可我们还能怎么办
Yeah, but what else can we do?
现在是彩翼鸟交配季
It's vertacine mating season.
不是吧
No way.
恭请各位上座
Your carriage awaits.
- 我要跟你亲个嘴 - 快走
- I'm gonna kiss you on the mouth! - Come on. Go, go.
好了 系好安全带 帅哥美女们
Buckle up, you beautiful people.
起飞了
Up and away. Yes!
糟糕 引擎失效了
No! The engine's out.
重力冲击波一定损坏了机上的什么能量电池
The gravity surge must have taken out the power-battery-thing.
好 太好了
Yes! Yes!
它在保护那些传送口
She's protecting the portals.
天啊
Oh, God!
巴西 里约热内卢
快看
Look.
吉雅 你没事 来
Jia, you're safe! Come here.
我太为你骄傲了
听着 我…
Look, I…
我知道 这个地方…
…让你有家的感觉
我就是想让你知道
不论你怎么决定
我都支持
你在说什么呀
我在说…
"What am I talking a…"
我以为你想留在地心
不论我们去哪里 去做什么…
…都要在一起
你可以在这里安家
我…
I…
有你就有家
没事吧
You all right? Yeah?
真的吗 好
Yeah? Yeah.
谢谢 谢谢了
Thank you, thank you.
我们就是擅长拯救世界
Yeah, saving the world is kind of our thing.